#### Kris Leech

Software Engineer, Trainer, Team Lead

Phone 07971 150 107

Mail <u>kris.leech@gmail.com</u>
Github <u>github.com/krisleech</u>

LinkedIn <u>uk.linkedin.com/in/krisleech</u>

Twitter <u>twitter.com/krisleech</u>
Blog <u>teamcoding.com</u>

# Introduction

Many years of working alongside talented people, on a diverse range of projects, has allowed me to learn, adapt and grow as an engineer. I aim to continually evolve my tools and techniques.

Building software in collaboration with great people in Agile teams is what makes me happy.

Fundamentally, I see transparency and open channels of communication as key to delivering a project which is successful for everyone involved.

- Practical experience with architectures such as DDD, DCI, Hexagonal Rails and SOA
- Delivery of 5 day RubyOnRails Training Courses
- In depth understanding of both TCP/IP and HTTP protocols
- Experience with provision and maintenance of Linux servers
- Knowledge of Search Engine Optimisation techniques
- Published and contributed to popular open source projects
- Familiarity with software vulnerabilities and their prevention

# **Education**

| 2010        | Introduction to Algorithms              | MIT OpenCourseWare (online)     |
|-------------|---|---------------------------------|
|             | Programming Methodology (CS106A)        | Stanford University (online)    |
|             | Programming Abstractions                | Stanford University (online)    |
|             | Programming Paradigms                   | Stanford University (online)    |
| 2009        | Internet Marketing and SEO              | E-business Club East Midlands   |
|             | Social Media and Web 2.0                | Connected Notts                 |
| 2003        | Website Design                          | Surrey School of Art and Design |
| 2002        | Network Security                        | Edwinstowe House                |
| 2002        | Search Engine Marketing                 | Edwinstowe House                |
| 1999 – 2001 | HND Sound Engineering                   | Confetti Studios, Nottingham    |
| 1999 – 2001 | AV (Audio / Video) Studies              | Intermedia, Nottingham          |
| 1998 – 1999 | Foundation Sound Engineering            | Confetti Studios, Nottingham    |
| 1998 – 1999 | A Levels - Computer Science, Psychology | People's College, Nottingham    |



| 1996 - 1998 | A Levels - Biology, Physics, Chemistry | Colonel Frank Seely,<br>Nottinghamshire |
|-------------|--|---|

# **Work Experience**

# 2014-present HouseTrip Limited

A leader in online holiday rentals (200+ employees), HouseTrip is a venture-backed start-up with an agile and international culture.

Role: Senior Software Engineer

- Development of conversion critical features built using Backbone.js
- Moving from a MonoRail to Service Orientated Architecture
- Driving decoupling of core business logic from Rails application
- Raise awareness of decoupling through discussions are isolated unit tests
- Negotiation of feature scope with PM's for AB testing of proposed features

#### 2001-2014 Interkonect Services UK Limited

Role: Managing Director, Lead Software Developer

Selected highlights:

• Lead developer on <u>Documas</u>, a workflow management platform for NHS Research studies.

The workflow of a research study is very complex involving geographically dispersed research teams with varying roles, compliance, multiple data sources, outdated browsers (IE 7) and regulatory reporting.

- Hired and managed a remote team
- Architectured a highly customizable Rails application for a very complex domain
- Worked directly with the clients to write user stories
- Lead the integration with third party regulatory HTTP services
- Transitioned the original app's UI written in ExtJS to plain HTML/JS
- Oversaw transition from Alfresco (SOAP/"REST"/ATOM) to our own RESTful service which wraps Camlistore
- Lead developer on <u>JobSavviGrad</u>, an employability portal with CV builder, aggregated Job search and automated Job application for University under graduates.
  - Moved a typical highly coupled manually tested 2 year old Rails app in the direction of a cleaner architecture which could respond to change.
  - Build a parallelizable Job board parsing framework using Capybara
  - Created an asynchronous (queue based) Job Application HTTP service
  - Architectured the product to a SaaS which could be provisioned and deployed with ease for each university.
- MVP for Boxhug, which won the Richard Branson Pitch to Rich award
- MVP for Matripa, a collaborative trip planner and marketplace
- Nottingham Information Prescriptions Nottinghamshire County Council

- Bassetlaw Health for the Nottingham City Clinical Commissioning Group
- Award winning <u>Back2You</u> remix competition website

# 2000-2001 Phizzie Design & Productions (self-employed)

Role: Web Developer

- EMNET delivery partner for the Curve project, providing European funding to SME's
- Selling the benefits of "open source" to the NHS
- Interactive CD-ROM's for Rushcliffe Primary Care Trust
- Design of the "The Coronary Heart Disease Toolkit" for Gedling Primary Care Trust
- Building content managed websites for small businesses
- Optimisation of websites for performance in search engines

# 2002-2004 Ericson Capital Limited

Role: Software Developer

- Development of new features for their EMAS accounting software product
- Working on a firewall-like product for network security
- Introduction of version control and a bug tracker
- Research in encrypted Ruby source code

# 2001-2002 Pacific Software Ltd

Role: Junior Software Developer

 Development of auxiliary tools for "Profit" a distributed client/server Delphi application which analysed live stock market feeds and allowed people to place trades through a broker

# 2000-2001 Sound Engineering for Mood Indigo

Role: Live Sound Engineer

- Live sound engineering for Mood Indigo gigs around the UK
- This included a large two night production at the Theatre Royal, Nottingham